globaltestmarket.com 2013-12-22

# GlobalTestMarket Privacy Policy

### GMI, including GMI's GlobalTestMarket, is committed to safeguarding your privacy online.

Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically. 

### Safe Harbor

GMI legal entities in the United States comply with the U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from the European Union and Switzerland. To view the GMI certification on the Safe Harbor list or to learn more about the Safe Harbor programs principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.   
If you have questions or concerns regarding our compliance with the U.S. E.U. and U.S. Swiss Safe Harbor framework, you should first contact us at <https://www.globaltestmarket.com/contact.php>. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry in 30 days, or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you have the option to contact American Arbitration Association (AAA), our third party Safe Harbor dispute resolution provider, register and file a claim at <https://apps.adr.org/webfile/>. 

### What personally identifiable information does GMI collect from me?

GMI collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of websites. Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, GMI asks for your name, email address, zip code, household information and personal interests. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to GMI -- you are given an account number which you will use to access the various protected areas of the site. Also, if you contact GMI, we may keep a record of that correspondence. Wherever GMI collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. 

### What are cookies and how does GMI use them?

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, GMI may use cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Some areas on GMI where you are prompted to log-in or that are customizable may require that you accept cookies. This avoids you having to enter your login information many times in one day. 

### Who is collecting information and for what purpose?

GMI collects valuable information which assists in developing new products and services. When you are on a GMI site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with GMI alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than GMI, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Promotions that run on GMI may be sponsored by companies other than GMI or may be co-sponsored by GMI and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared.

Any sensitive information (i.e. personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual) will be treated with additional care. If GMI intends to disclose such information to a third party or use it for a different purpose than originally collected, then you will be expressly asked permission prior to any such disclosure.

Please be aware that GMI advertisers or websites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those websites linked to GMI are not covered by this privacy statement.

### With whom does GMI share my information?

As a general rule, GMI will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Use or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. 

Business Partners and Sponsors: GMI may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. If any personal data about were ever to be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data.

Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give GMI permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer.

From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt in to receive information from these third parties, GMI will (with your permission) share your name and email address with them.

Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate: Under confidentiality agreements, GMI may match user information with third party data. Also, GMI discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

Other: GMI may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating GMI's Terms of Use or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) GMI's rights or property, other GMI users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. GMI may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.

### What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?

Only GMI (or agents working on behalf of GMI and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. 

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you would like to opt-out of only the GMI cookies, the GMI domain for your reference is either gmi-mr.com or globaltestmarket.com. If you choose to reject all cookies or opt-out of accepting GMI cookies you will be unable to use those GMI services that require registration in order to participate.

GMI does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service.

### What is GMI's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?

For members of GMI's GlobalTestMarket, you may edit your GlobalTestMarket Account Information and your GlobalTestMarket Profile at any time by using your GlobalTestMarket ID and password. If you have forgotten your password, please click here. Your GlobalTestMarket account can be deleted or deactivated. You can choose to terminate your membership at any time by completing this form. 

For users of any of GMI's other products and services, you can [contact us](http://www.gmi-mr.com/contact/) if you have forgotten your login or password. Please also [contact us](http://www.gmi-mr.com/contact/) with any questions regarding access to personally identifiable information.

### What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?

Your Account Information and Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. 

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. GMI will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your GMI account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

Whenever GMI handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, GMI takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, GMI cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

### What else should I know about my privacy?

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online -- for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas -- that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

### Additional Information

Please contact us with any questions regarding this statement.
